Guide to the Pundits, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Pundits, Yale University, records
1884-2016
RU 308
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.58
12 boxes
48.9
The records consist of correspondence, photographs, pledge sheets, clippings, and miscellaneous files documenting the endeavors of the Yale Pundits.
Yale University. Pundits
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Pundits, 1996-2010 and 2015-2016.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. Written permission of president of organization required.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Pundits was founded in 1884 by members of the Class of 1887 and survived for one year. It appeared again in 1899, 1903, and in 1994. The plan of its meetings called for the chosen writer "to set up an ideal as an idol," which the other members were to demolish if possible. One of their first deeds was the establishment of a prize for an essay "on some need of the College and how it may be supplied, or on some tendency of a feature contrary to the welfare of the College, and how it may best be amended." Like its predecessors, the Pundits plan and execute pranks directed toward other Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, photographs, pledge sheets, clippings, and miscellaneous files documenting the endeavors of the Yale Pundits.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Pundits
- Records, 1903-1911; Accession 19ND-A-482
  - Records, 1903-1911 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia, 1992-1996; Accession 1997-A-041
  - Memorabilia, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
- Records, 1994-1997; Accession 1998-A-028
  - Miscellaneous, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - E-mail correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and pledge sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Records, 1957-2006; Accession 2007-A-137
  - Activities, 1995-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1957-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Records, 1884-2007; Accession 2008-A-031
  - Class and signature lists, 1884-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emergency phone tree, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History, 1884-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Play list, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Activities, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reunion, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yale Class Book/Banner info on Pundits, 1952-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Computer files (Box 2–4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
    - Activities, 21
      General note
      Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Alumni directory, 1991-2006; computer file (XLS)
    - Newsclippings, 4
- Records, 2008-2010; Accession 2010-A-075; 0.25
  - Bazaar for Undergraduate Organizations, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes and email, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Records, 2009-2010; Accession 2010-A-084; 3.5; (2 boxes)
  - Internal documents re: recruitment and tap, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News clippings and ephemera, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pundits screw [novelty handcuffs] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sash from first party (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Yale Literary Magazine (XXI:II) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gift to TBIYTB from 2008 alum [dong bong]
  - Kissing poster (Folder 2)
  - John Gaddis, "Art of Biography Seminar," Titanic prank poster (Folder 2)
  - Mock up copy of Yale Literary Magazine (XXII: I) (Folder 2)
- Records, 2013-2015; Accession 2016-A-028
  - Correspondence (pranks), 2013-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News clippings, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Overheard at Yale" Facebook group, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parent's weekend Apple product coupon prank, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Angels" playbill: playwright Otis Blum dedicates show to the Pundits, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Rumpus" Yale student magazine, 2015 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rush invitation, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Records, 2012-2013; Accession 2016-A-053
  - Event invitations, ephemera, news clippings, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Event posters, Accession 2016-A-057
  - Event posters (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Undated posters hung on main campus by members of Pundits during a visit by Mr. Charles B. Johnson '54.
- Records, 2015-2016; Accession 2017-A-011
  - News clippings and ephemera, 2015-2016 (Box 1, Folder 1)